Pavan Raga

www.github.com/pavanraga • www.linkedin.com/in/pavanraga • pavan.raga@u.nus.edu • +65-98612663
463 Pasir Panjang Rd, Singapore 118797

About Me

Highly skilled software engineer with more than 5 years of experience in software development and DevOps. I'm seeking a DevOps Engineer/Consultant role involving infrastructure systems or backend development. I'm passionate about immutable, reliable, automated infrastructure that scales optimally with organizational needs.

Work Experience

Dyson Singapore

DevOps Engineer - Intern

Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

- Developing an internal platform to detect the best suited object detection algorithm given a data-set.
- Deploying the services using docker compose locally for testing and re-deploying the same to managed cloud offerings such as EKS by AWS for production use.

WalletSocket - Cloud Team

Singapore

DevOps Engineer - PT

Aug 2019 - Jan 2020

- Assisted in design and architect of the Pay0k platform which is a payment gateway for merchants to accept various cryptocurrencies like bitcoin, ethereum.
- Responsible for developing and maintaining the CI/CD pipeline for both staging and production environments.
- Utilized Kubernetes extensively to orchestrate the life cycle of polyglot microservices. Followed best practices to develop manifests and integrating the same with continuous delivery.
- Handled increasing traffic load by scaling the backend services/container horizontally by using K8s HPA.
- Implemented application monitoring using Grafana/prometheus and k8s WebUI.
- Deployed replicated MongoDB using helm to provide high fault tolerance for the persistent layer.

Cisco Systems Inc

Bangalore, India

Software Engineer II

Apr 2018 - Jun 2019

- Independently worked on "Cisco-Capture" tool to enhance the debuggability in live deployments by capturing control and data traffic.
- Moved monolothic application to configure routers to containerized application and deployed them in k8s cluster to provide fault tolerance.

Cisco Systems Inc

Bangalore, India

Software Engineer I

Mar 2016 - *May* 2018

- Developed Layer 2 features of ASR 903 series of service aggregation routers.
- Implemented Dying Gasp support to minimise down time during power outages.
- Built "Autonomous Networking" feature to enable zero touch deployments. This is pull-based infrastructure as Code tool.

AllGo Embedded Systems

Bengalore, India

Software Engineer

Iul 2014 - Feb 2016

- Part of Mirrorlink stack team, a stack which helps in replicating the smartphones display on to car's HMI/infotainment unit.
- Developed CI of software commits using Jenkins to enable fast delivery.
- Built a recovery module for HMI by detecting unhealthy application in the unit and respawning them.

Education

National University of Singapore (NUS) GPA: 4.0/5.0

Singapore

Master of Technology in Software Engineering

Jun 2019 - Jul 2020

• Architecting Cloud Native Scalable Systems, Securing Ubiquitous Systems and Engineering Big Data

• Developed pay0k platform for WalletSocket and deployed into production for south korea region in Jan 2020.

National Institute of Engineering (NIE) GPA: 8.99/10

Mysuru, India

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

Jun 2010 - Sep 2014

Professional Certifications

• Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA) Issued by: Linux Foundation

Feb 2020

• AWS Certified Solutions Architect(ACSAA) Issued by: AWS

Apr 2019

Keywords

Languages: Python, C, YAML.

Infrastructure: Kubernetes, Docker, Amazon Web Service, DigitalOcean, Google Cloud Platform

Monitoring/Log: Grafana, Prometheus, Elasticsearch, Kibana, Logstash Tools: Jenkins, Ansible, Jira, Wireshark, VS Code, Git, Docker, Nginx